Good afternoon,
Добрый день
evening, I am from Ukraine, the city of Khmelnitsky,
вечер я из Украины город Хмельницкий Вы
where are you from, Russia, the city of Belgorod,
откуда из России город Белгород
mikross, the USSR, that is, the USSR,
майкросс СССР то есть СССР
I was born in the USSR,
Я родился в СССР
here are the people who both of us were born in the
вот людей которые вот мы оба родились в
USSR, that is, fresh in one country,
СССР то есть при свежили в одной стране
how are you like the USSR Rate
как вот вы как СССР Оцените то что
what you rate  that your country is bombing
как вы оцените что ваша страна бомбит
my country, too, such the USSR
мою страну тоже такие СССР
Well, I want to tell you that this is the
Ну я вам хочу сказать что это одна и та
same country,
же страна
what it is called She calls It used to
как она называется Она называет Раньше
be called the Russian Empire, then
она называлась Российская империя потом
in the twenty-twenty-second year it
в двадцатом двадцать втором году
was rebranded, it became
произошел ребрендинг она стала
known as the Soviet Union in 91 happened
называться Советский Союз в 91 году
again
опять
the collapse of this country
развал этой страны
First it was
Сначала был
then in 91 collapse And now
потом в 91 развал А сейчас возвращаются
these lands are returning
эти земли
good branding and called themselves the USSR And how
добрый брендинг и назвался СССР А как
then this country was called, for example, in the
тогда эта страна называлась например в
twentieth in 19 and 18,
двадцатом в 19 и 18 году
Russian as it is now I will tell the
Российская как это сейчас расскажу
Russian kingdom The
российское царство
Russian Empire so the Russian
Российская империя так Российская
Empire in 1917 ceased to
империя в 1917 году перестала
exist  and 17 to 22
существовать а 17 по 22 год
years such events took place, parts of this
происходили вот такие события части этой
country declared independence but
страны заявляли о независимости но
It turned out that these parts cannot
Выяснилось что эти части не могут
exist on their own, but what was the name of that
существовать но как называлась как та
very main part from the capital there in
самая главная часть со столицы там в
St. Petersburg or Moscow, what was it called in
Петербурге или Москве как она называлась
the seventeenth year, it ceased
вот семнадцатом году она перестала
to be called the Russian Empire, and on the 22nd it began
называться Российской империи а 22 начал
to be
назваться
called it was called like me so much history
называлась как я так сильно историю
Tell me then I remember
Расскажите вы мне тогда я помню вот я
when I was in the Soviet Union, I
еще когда был в Советском Союзе я
went to school a little bit. They still studied there, and they
немножко школу Там еще учился да нам
told us that it was the Russian
рассказывали что было Российская империя
Empire, and then the February Maidan happened.
так и потом произошел Февральский Майдан
October the second Maidan took place there
октябре произошёл второй Майдан там у
you had a terrorist organization
вас было террористическая организация
left sector Yes there is Lenin Here they also
левый сектор Да там Ленина Вот они ещё
made Maidans so that is, uh, and it
сделали майданы так вот то есть э и
turns out this is the most important
получается этого самого главного
terrorist, or now the sector is now in the
террориста или вот сектора сейчас в
Mausoleum that essentially buried the
Мавзолей которые по сути похоронил
Russian Empire so it turns out
Российскую империю так получается
unambiguously yes, that is, uh  if Russia
однозначно да то есть э если Россия это
is the Russian Empire So why is the
есть Российская империя Так почему
killer of the Russian Empire Le  nin lies in the
убийца Российской империи Ленин лежит в
center of Moscow in a place of honor
центре Москвы в почетном месте потому
because this is already a moment in history, no more
что это уже момент истории не больше
just Russia now It tries not to
просто Россия сейчас Она старается не
stir up the wounds of various segments of the population
ворошить раны различных слоев населения
and generations, and therefore the task of any
и поколений и поэтому задача любого
state is not to create conflicts in
государства это не создавать конфликты в
society Who has what language, who has what
обществе У кого какой язык у кого какая
faith Who has  what national heroes,
вера У кого какие национальные герои а
namely, to cement society so that all,
именно цементировать общество чтобы все
let's say, active elements show their activity
скажем активные элементы свою активность
, let's say, not on the Maidans, but on
проявляли скажем Не на майданах а на
some lines, I can’t understand why
каких-либо строках не могу понять зачем
then Russia, we all lived normally in the USSR
тогда вот Россия мы жили все в СССР
Why did Russia begin to
нормально Зачем Россия начала
rename Soviet cities like that,
переименовать города советские так
for example, there was Gorky
наставила например там был Горький стал
Samara became Kalinin became Tver a monument to
Самара был Калинин стал Тверь памятник
Dzerzhinsky gave in Moscow climbed
дзержинскому дал в Москве забрались
why it is so
почему это так
I want to tell you that it was not
я вам хочу сказать что это делала не
Russia who did it, these were the deeds of those
Россия это дела те
leaders of
лидеры
Russia who were in power at that moment
России которые были в тот момент у
Well, that is, it was Russia that did not
власти Ну то есть это Россия не
represent Russia, they represented
представляли Россию они представляли
Russia, they represented Russia
Россию они представляли Россию
this is Russia's business, it was a lot
это дело России это было очень много
of very stupid posts  upkov now
совершено очень глупых поступков сейчас
Leningrad region
Ленинградская область
city of st. petersburg oblast
город санкт-петербург область
Leningradskaya city of st. petersburg
Ленинградская город санкт-петербург Как
Do you think the name should be returned again
вы считаете надо вернуть название снова
Leningrad and not st.
Ленинград А не санкт-петербург так
it turns out, that is, the
Подождите стоп э получается как то есть
inhabitants of Leningrad can call it
жители Ленинграда могут назвать его
st. petersburg and the inhabitants of the Leningrad
санкт-петербург а жители Ленинградской
region vote that the
области проголосовать что область
Leningrad region turns out that way.
Ленинградская так получается
I think that the inhabitants of st.
Я думаю что жители санкт-петербурга если
they will have
там продвинутые Поэтому если у них будет
some kind of initiative and then they
какая-либо инициатива и они потом
will hold a referendum there or something else
проведут референдум там или еще что-либо
as they want, letting go and resolving these
как они захотят отпуская и решают эти
issues. I don’t think that these issues are
вопросы Я не думаю что эти вопросы
fundamental, but Gorky was Nizhny
принципиальные а Горький это Нижний
Novgorod. Yes, it just turns out that
Новгород был Да просто получается что
look like I don’t understand why here
смотрите как бы я не понимаю почему вот
in Russia they did if it's like the rulers
в России сделали если это типа правители
did nick  munization and why
сделали никомунизацию да то почему не
won’t these Soviet names be returned, it’s
вернут эти названия советских это же
ours when you say Leningrad
наши вот когда говоришь Ленинград
the hero city everyone understands when
город-герой все понимают был когда
Leningrad was but no one blockade
Ленинграда но никто не Блокада
st.
согласен я вам я вам хочу сказать одну
that is, Putin is a dark axiom
понимаете то есть Путин темный аксиома
Putin is a dark personality is not the best
Путин темная личность не самая лучшая
personality Putin and any leader
личность Путин и любое руководитель
any leader
любой руководитель
you said here is a real axiom I believed in it
вы сказали вот реальную аксиому Я в неё
that they don’t get to power of a bright personality
поверил что к власти светлой личности не
if a person in power is already, according to the
если человек при власти он уже по
axiom, not a Bright personality Well, this is mine, it
аксиоме не Светлая личность Ну это моё
turns out that
получается что
Putin is a dark personality
Путин темная личность
Putin is too soft A person is a dark
Путин слишком мягкий Человек он темная
personality because he got to power
личность потому что он добрался к власти
Well, I don’t know what kind of skeletons he has hanging in the
Ну я не знаю какие у него там скелеты в
closet Well, I don’t like
шкафу висят Ну меня пути не устраивает
the way that he is too soft with his hand
то что он слишком мягкий рукой аксиома
the authorities do not
что светлые личности к власти не
get it
добирают
once Putin got to power, he means, according to
раз Путин добрался к власти он значит по
this axiom, we deduce the investigation of Thu  oh he’s
этой аксиоме мы выводим следствие что он
not a light personality Putin a dark
не Светлая личность Путин темная
personality
личность
turns out to be the darkest Stalin was also a dark
получается Сталин тоже было темная
Well, nevertheless,
Ну тем не менее
to pay
отдать отдать
tribute to Stalin, didn’t he just do it now,
Сталину должное что ли сейчас не сделал
just the industry raised the light
просто промышленность поднял светлые
dark ones, that is, in the Soviet dark
темные то есть в Советском темная
personality, you recognize this Shpak
личность вы это признаете это Шпак
by forces, really,
силами правда
tell me the light parts  there are no axioms in power yet
назовите мне светлые части у власти еще
He says that there are no bright personalities in power,
нет аксиомаш Говорит что у власти нету
we understand that Lenin was Dark
мы понимаем что Ленин был Тёмная
personality Stalin Dark personality Brezhnev
личность Сталин Тёмная личность Брежнев
Dark personality Khrushchev Dark personality
Тёмная личность Хрущёв Тёмная личность
Yeltsin There and so on All dark
Ельцин Там и так далее Все тёмные
personalities and Putin Now you are very
личности и Путин Сейчас вы сейчас очень
good for me in Ukraine it all worked
хорошо для меня в Украине это всё
out
сложилось
it’s very good that for you that Putin is a
очень хорошо что для вас что Путин - это
Dark personality I thought that he was
Тёмная личность Я думал что он светлый
some kind of light what I call this stupidity
какой-то что это глупость я называю
and from here comes the consequence that Putin is a
и отсюда идёт следствие что Путин
dark personality and Kadyrov Ramzan
темная личность а Кадыров Рамзан Вот у
He also has power in Chechnya Yes he is the
него тоже есть власть в Чечне Да он
head of Chechnya, he turns out too  dark
глава Чечни он получается тоже темная
personality
личность
I suggest you if you are interested You
я я вам предлагаю если вам интересно Вы
can study the history of any
можете изучить историю любого
leadership  and draw
руководителя и самостоятельно сделать
conclusions on my own, I’ve done it, look I used to
выводы я вот сделал смотрите Я раньше
study, but I didn’t have enough of a
изучал но мне не хватало кого-то
connecting element And now this
связующего элемента А теперь хватило это
axiom was enough, she just knows how it
аксиома она просто знаете как
cements it’s great
цементирует это здорово
By the way, my name is Andrey And what is your name
Кстати меня зовут Андрей А Вас как зовут
Thank you so much you
Вам огромнейшее спасибо вы мне
turn out to me that you proved  that Ramzan
получается что вы доказали что Рамзан
Kadyrov A dark personality
Кадыров Тёмная личность
and now I can carry Sveta A
а теперь я могу нести Света
dark personality
Тёмная личность
at home is cool and cool But you are a
дома это круто да прикольно А вот вы
light personality or a dark one By the way,
Светлая личность или темная Кстати я и
I can’t be put in power
меня нельзя ставить во власть
That is, you are dark Yes, I will execute
То есть вы темные Да я буду Всех казнить
everyone among the majority That is, you are such a couch tyrant  Yes,
То есть вы такой диванный тиран Да вот
sit here If I were pinache there I’m shorter than the
сидите Если бы я был пиначе там Я короче
village to rest now it will be what we
поселка отдыхать сейчас будет что мы
did if you instead of Putin
сделали вот если вы вас вместо Путина
became the leader of Russia
стали главырем России
you darkened Here you are now a bright
вы потемнели Вот вы сейчас светлый
person but you would become dark in Russia
человек но стали бы в России потемнели
right away what did you do with the population of Russia
сразу что вы сделали с населением России
go
идти
with the population  Russia Nothing, I would force
с населением России Ничего я заставил бы
officials to fulfill their duties,
чиновников исполнять свои обязанности
why, well, it is necessary to punish officials
зачем ну нужно наказывать чиновников тех
who they have fulfilled  do
которые они выполняются
n’t buy fashionable Cars for yourself so that your
не покупай себе модные Тачки чтобы твой
son doesn’t carry watches for a bunch of tens of
сын не таскал часы за кучу там десятков
thousands of dollars there,
тысяч долларов
why can’t he buy Why is
почему он не может покупать Почему так у
his salary not enough for such where
него зарплаты не хватает на такое откуда
does he need to ask a question not to buy,
у него вопрос нужно задавать не покупать
but to make people any any official
а чтобы люди любые любой чиновник
responsible for their purchases  your salary,
отвечал за свои покупки своей зарплаты
how would you like Ramzan Kadyrov
как бы вы например Рамзана Кадырова
Imagine that you are now the head of Russia,
Представьте что вы сейчас глава России
how would you hold Ramzan Kadyrov to account
как бы вы притянули к ответу Рамзана
for the fact that he squanders Russian money
Кадырова за то что он разбазарит деньги
squanders Russian money And
разбазаривает российские деньги А вы
when you were last in Grozny,
когда были последний раз в Грозном
I saw For example, the
смотрите Я видел Вот например новости
news meant that he  my son showed up with a
было значит что его сын засветился с
watch there, several tens of thousands of
часами там несколько десятков тысяч
dollars, for example, I understood everything, I understood,
долларов например Всё я понял я понял
I want to tell you more that
я больше вам хочу сказать что
poor people poor people are very well
нищие люди нищие люди очень хорошо
versed in expensive models of watches for
разбираются в дорогих моделях часов
cars and houses.
автомобилей и домов А вот вы смотрите Вы
so with an eye on
России и вы смотрите так глазом на
Ramzan Kadyrov I don’t want I don’t want to
Рамзана Кадырова его Я не хочу я не хочу
be the head of Russia Not well if you become  And
быть главой России Не ну если вы стали А
how good How the head of Russia, the correct
как хорошо Как глава России правильный
head of Russia should deal with Ramzan
глава России должен поступить с рамзаном
Kadyr so that he does not squander
кадыром чтобы он не разбазаривал деньги
Russian money who told you that he is
российские кто вам сказал что
squandered Where does Ramzan Kadyrov come from
разбазаривается Откуда у Рамзана
?
ребятам на бронники не хватает а у него
a few dozen that
несколько десятков что
Well, how something is to take everything away and
Ну как что то есть все отобрать и
share it for me just Sharikov, so this is the
поделить мне просто Шарикова так это
USSR it is written to take everything away and share the
СССР написано всё отобрать и поделить
word told you that it is only
слово вам сказал что отобрать только у
written on your
вас на майке СССР написано у меня на
T-shirt of the USSR that it is written on my T-shirt USSR that what it is
майке написано СССР что что это же есть
to take away and divide this  said Well, the
отобрать и поделить такое сказал Ну так
logic of the communists was taken
логика коммунистов была отобрать
seriously Yes,
серьёзно Да
for example, some official is sitting in the
например сидит какой-то чиновник в
city of Bryansk and watching a badge if
городе Брянск и смотрит бляха если
Kadyrov can be so shamelessly shorter to
Кадырову можно так безбожно короче
steal and buy watches for tens of
воровать и своим детям часы за десятки
thousands of dollars for your children that you
тысяч долларов покупать что мне не
can’t let me, uh
можешь давайте э-э
No, let me ask you a question  having asked, let's ask
Нет давайте я вам вопрос задавшись задам
you, are you afraid of Kadyrov Let me
давайте вы боитесь Кадырова Давайте я
ask you, let me ask you now,
вам задавать давайте я теперь задам
well, look at the Kremlin for the last  In the last
хорошо вот смотрите Кремль за последние
10 years I imprisoned 14 governors 14
10 лет посадил 14 губернаторов 14
governors over the past 10 years I imprisoned the
губернаторов за последние 10 лет посадил
Kremlin for economic criminal
Кремль за экономические уголовные
offenses my question to you how many of their
преступления мой вопрос к вам сколько их
governors in Ukraine have been imprisoned over the
губернаторов в Украине посадили за
past 10 years for economic
последние 10 лет за экономические
crimes in Ukraine and our governors we have
преступления у нас и губернаторов у нас
pain 0
боль 0
understand 0 l everything that you answer  Or maybe
понимаете 0 л все что вам ответ А может
they don’t steal so godlessly in Russia How did
у нас так не ворует безбожно Как в
they tell you this in Russia?
России что вам такое сказал Просто я вот
watches of perfumes and cars
дорогих марках часов духов и автомобилей
I love it so much when every Russian is
Я так люблю когда вот Каждый русский он
so brave that when he walks he
настолько смелый что когда идёт
remembers in vain the name of Kadyrov they immediately have an
вспоминает всуе имя Кадырова у них сразу
internal mop, more precisely, an internal
внутренняя швабра точнее внутреннее
core Yes, an
стержень Да
inner core such
внутренний стержень такой
immediately And where does Kadyrov
сразу А причем здесь Кадыров
and you start to evade And
причем вы бы вы начинаете увиливать А
why doesn’t he have I  I can’t
почему у него нет Я же не могу
comment on the inflammation of your
комментировать воспаление вашего
brain, I understand, yes, you understand
головного мозга понял да понимаете
about K  Adyrov you can’t do anything you
насчет Кадырова вы ничего не можете вы
can about Ukrainian governors 14
можете про украинский губернаторов 14
Russian governors gave an example But
губернаторов российских привёл пример А
you can’t do anything
вы ничего не можете
Here are 14 governors who imprisoned this you
Вот 14 губернаторов посадили это вы
can comment on
можете комментировать
Kadyrov we can’t Let
Кадырова не можем А давайте давайте мы
’s criticize Kadyrov now Let’s go
сейчас покритикуем Кадырова Давай давай
What’s there What did you say about
Что там Что там у вас рассказали про
Kadyrov see  I just remember even before the
Кадыров смотрите Я просто помню ещё до
start of the war So I was
начала войны Так что Кадыров я был
little Kadyrov really then Yes I remember that
маленький правда тогда Да помню что
Kadyrov fought against Russia and
Кадыров воевал и против России да и
killed Russians yes it turns out But now
убивал русских да получается А теперь
they gave him the Hero of Russia and somehow it
ему дали Героя России и у меня как-то в
doesn’t add up in my head That’s all bad It’s
голове не складывается Вот всё плохо Это
bad  what doesn’t add up in your head
плохо что у вас не складывается в голове
Help, they taught history very badly How
Помогите очень плохо учили историю Как
Kadyrov killed Russians in Russia
Кадыров убивал русских в России
and for this he was given, uh, Hero of Russia, he
а за это ему дали э-э Героя России он
now leads the
теперь руководит
subject of the Russian Federation, the subject of the
субъектом Российской Федерации субъектом
Russian Federation, you understand
Российской Федерации понимаете Если бы
If If you had more, let’s say,
Если бы у вас было более скажем
meaningful thinking more  meaningful
осмысленное мышление более осмысленное
thinking, then you could appreciate that
мышление то вы бы могли оценить что
Kodyrov's father He was stopped by the civil
кодыров отец Его остановили гражданскую
war in Chech  it was not a very serious
войну в Чечне это очень серьёзный был
conflict within the country, and when there was a
конфликт внутри страны и когда была
civil war in Chechnya,
Гражданская война в Чечне
Tatarstan spoke about its independence
Татарстан говорил о своей Независимости
there, Siberia and the like,
там Сибири и тому подобное
you want to hear my opinion.
вы хотите услышать моё мнение
So Kadyrov, he had the courage to
Вот и Кадыров ему хватило мужество
stop the civil war, calm the
остановить гражданскую войну успокоить
entire Caucasus, and now thanks to
весь Кавказ и сейчас благодаря тому
what has been done now  The Caucasus
что было сделано сейчас Кавказ спокойно
lives quietly without any conflicts, without any
живет без всяких конфликтов без всяких
times, and You see, But this is
раз и Понимаете вот Но это Это
impossible to understand for people who sit and
невозможно понять людям которые сидят и
watch Through a magnifying glass they look at
смотрят Через лупу смотрят
someone else's grain of sand
чужую песчинку
and then they said let's stop
а потом они сказали давайте мы остановим
now, not the heroes of Russia
теперь не герои России
Well, I told you once, maybe you can be
Ну я вам один раз сказал может быть вам
from once  it’s not clear
с одного раза не понятно
Well, I can only sympathize
Ну я могу вам только посочувствовать в
with you that you have a very meager outlook, you
том что у вас очень скудной Кругозор вы
understand yes You can, for example, a killer He
понимаете да Можно например убийца Он
killed a man and now I’m against murder
убил человека а теперь я против убийств
Well done On you Hero of Russia
Молодец На тебя Герой России
[music]
[музыка]
[laughter]
[смех]
oh funny
ой смешно
it would be like that it wouldn’t be like that  funny If
было бы так не было бы так смешно Если
it weren't so bitter bitter really
бы не было так горько горько реально
so many Russian soldiers
столько русских солдатиков мальчиков
defenseless boys for Russian soldiers  ticks are
беззащитных за русские солдатиков
worried
переживают
I’m worried you’re running away cockroaches killing Russians on the territory of the Russian Federation I understand
я понимаю
it’s great if only you
лишь бы вам
all the Yakuns descend internal mop
якуны всех спускаются внутренние швабра
Kadyrov’s condom just that is,
презерватив Кадырова просто то есть
officials put 14 governors all
чиновники посадили 14 губернатором все
yes like I want Kadyrov’s son in short hours
да типа хочу сына Кадырова короче часы
for several tens of thousands of dollars and
за несколько десятков тысяч долларов а
this is you poor  Because you pay
это ты бедный Потому что ты обращаешь
attention What kind of watch Cars and perfume
внимание Какие часы Тачки и духи